Guide to the Frederick Albert Pottle Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writing and Research Files, 1913-1979; Series III
  - "Wordsworth and Freud, or the Theory of the Unconscious", undated (Box 22, Folder 139)
  - Untitled book
    - "Algernon Charles Swinburne", undated (Box 22, Folder 140)
    - "Emotional Romanticism - A Chapter of Definitions", undated (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - "William Blake", undated (Box 23, Folder 142)
  - Book reviews, 1942-1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 143)
  - Background files
    - General, undated (Box 23, Folder 144-146)
    - Boswell
      - Periodical extracts, 1925-1927 (Box 23, Folder 147)
      - False attributions, 1925-1927 (Box 23, Folder 148)
      - Journal of a Tour of the Hebrides, 1925-1935 (Box 23, Folder 149)
      - The Decision...on the Question of Literary Property, 1925-1935 (Box 23, Folder 150)
      - Life of Johnson [includes correspondence], 1926-1935 (Box 23, Folder 151)
      - Posthumous publications, 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 152)
      - An Account of Corsica, 1933-1940 (Box 23, Folder 153)
      - The Essence of the Douglas Case, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 154)
    - Ronaldson's collection of original poems by Scottish Gentlemen, [1760-1762], undated (Box 23, Folder 155)
- Personal Papers, 1861-1974; Series IV
  This series contains biographical material, partial bibliographies of Pottle's writings, loose clippings and scrapbooks of writings by and about Pottle, and memorabilia. A few student notebooks, class papers, and lists of accessions to Pottle's library are also included. The series incorporates books, articles, and letters associated with Reverend James Gammack, who was rector emeritus at St. James Church, West Hartford, Connecticut at the time of his death in 1923. These were probably the gift of Pottle's friend, John Wilson Gammack. The photographs include portraits of Pottle and pictures of his family, friends, and associates.
  - American Field Service [application to French universities], 1924 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Autobiographical note, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography, 1923-1966 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Biographical sketches, [196-] (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1927-1970, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Gammack, James
    - Correspondence, 1861-1899 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Jacobite Songs, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Obituaries, 1923 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Writings, 1881-1923 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Legal and financial papers, 1897, 1938-1947 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Library accessions, 1919-1940 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Memorabilia
    - General, 1917-1974 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Europe, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - New Hampshire State College, 1921-1923 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Photographs
    - Pottle, Frederick Albert, 1936-1974, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - People and places, 1918-1971 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbooks [articles by and about Pottle], 1920-1949 (Box 26, Folder 18-20)
  - Student papers, 1920-1924 (Box 27, Folder 21-28)
  - Tributes to Pottle, 1969-1972 (Box 27, Folder 29)